Guide to the Henry O'Reilly Papers 1819-1880 (Bulk 1844-1860) MS 464
New-York Historical Society
Henry O'Reilly papers
1819-1880 (Bulk 1844-1860)
New-York Historical Society
O'Reilly, Henry, 1806-1886
O'Rielly, Henry
MS 464
28 Linear feet
The Papers of Henry O'Reilly, dating from 1832 to 1873, consist of 28 linear feet of material. The bulk of these papers date from 1844 to 1860. The O'Reilly Papers contain the following types of material: business and personal correspondence (letters, telegraph messages), minutes, proceedings, organizational documents (charters, by-laws, articles of incorporation and association), financial documents (bills, receipts, invoices, expenditure sheets, accounts, bank drafts, promissory notes, inventories, stock certificates), legal documents (contracts, conveyances, indentures, deeds, leases, affidavits, depositions, insurance policies, mortgages, memoranda), notes, reports, scrapbooks, and printed material (pamphlets, proofs, circulars, flyers, clippings).
Access Restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Biographical Note
Missing Title
1806 Born in Carrickmacross, Province of Ulster, Ireland
1816 Came to New York, New York, Learned printer's trade
1823 Assistant Editor of the New York Patriot
1826 Moved to Rochester, New York
1826-1830 Editor of the Rochester Daily Advertiser
1832 Appointed Deputy Collector and Inspector for the District of Genesee, New York
1833 Began advocating rebuilding and enlargement of the Erie Canal
1838 Appointed Post Master of Rochester, Published Sketches of Rochester
[1839] President of Rochester Athenaeum and Young Men's Association
[1844] Recording Secretary, New York State Agricultural Society
1845 Entered into contract with Samuel F.B. Morse and Amos Kendall for erecting telegraph lines in the United States
1851 Established Irish and American Steamship Company
1854 Organized Demoine Navigation and Railroad Company
1859 Chairman of Clinton League
1886 Died in Rochester, New York
Henry O'Reilly was born in Carrickmacross, Province of Ulster, Ireland on Feb. 6, 1806 to a merchant and the daughter of a physician. In 1816, the family emigrated to New York. After working as an apprentice in the printing trade including several years as an assistant editor of the New York Patriot, in 1826 O'Reilly was appointed editor of the Rochester, NY, Daily Advertiser. Within a year, O'Reilly gained notice in the anti-Masonic uproar that followed the kidnapping and murder of William Morgan. In 1832, he was appointed Deputy Collector and Inspector for the District of Genesee, NY. He published numerous circulars and pamphlets on current events and issues, and in 1838 Sketches of Rochester, with Incidental Notices of Western New York. In that same year, O'Reilly was appointed Post Master of Rochester. From the 1830s through the 1850s, he was heavily involved in civic and political organizations, serving as the President of the Rochester Athenaeum and Young Men's Association, Recording Secretary of the New York State Agricultural Society, and Chairman of the Clinton League.
O'Reilly's commercial activities were similarly energetic and varied. In 1833, he threw his support behind improvements to the Erie Canal. In 1845, he contracted with Samuel F.B. Morse and Amos Kendall in the planned construction of telegraph wires from eastern Pennsylvania to the Great Lakes. Legal difficulties ended his involvement with the enterprise, despite his erection of over 8,000 miles of wire. In 1851, O'Reilly established the Irish and American Steamship Company; in 1854, he organized the Demoine Navigation and Railroad Company.
O'Reilly was married to Marcia Brooks, daughter of General Micah Brooks; they had one son, Henry Brooks O'Reilly, who was killed in the Battle of Williamsburg, 1862. Late in his life, O'Reilly changed the spelling of his surname to O'Rielly; additional papers of O'Reilly may be found under this variant.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Henry O'Reilly, dating from 1819-1880, consist of 28 linear feet of material. The bulk of the papers date from 1844 to 1860 and include the following forms: business and personal correspondence, minutes, proceedings, organizational records, financial records, legal records, notes, reports, scrapbooks and printed matter.
The O'Reilly Papers document the diverse activities of Henry O'Reilly in Rochester, NY; the Genesee District; and New York State. Specific topics addressed include: the establishment of telegraph lines; the development, improvement and operations of the transportation industry, particularly canals, steamships and railroads; local and state politics; civic and cultural organizations; journalism; typography; American Indians; agriculture; government reform; the postal service; public schools; land purchases in Western Virginia; and the military career of O'Reilly's son.
Arrangement
Correspondence within series are usually arranged alphabetically for letters received, chronologically for letters sent. Unidentified letters received and correspondence between others arranged chronologically.
The documents have been arranged in twenty-four series, the last of which includes materials inventoried and added to the finding aid in April 2022. Many of the series have been arranged in subseries.
Series I: General Correspondence, 1837-1872
Series II: Telegraph Enterprise, 1844-1861
Series III: Demoine Navigation and Railroad Company, 1849-1858
Series IV: Erie Canal Enlargement, 1836-1841
Series V: Clinton League, 1859
Series VI: New York State Agricultural Society, 1841-1856
Series VII: Politics, 1836-1857
Series VII: Post Office, Rochester, 1838-1844
Series IX: Common Schools, Rochester, 1838-1840
Series X: Rochester Athenaeum and Young Men's Association, 1838-1840
Series XI: Western Virgina Lands, 1838-1856
Series XII: Albany Irish Repeal Association, 1843
Series XIII: American Indians, 1838-1860
Series XIV: Deputy Collector and Inspector of District of Genesee, 1832-1842
Series XV: Irish and American Steamship Company, 1851
Series XVI: New York Typographical Society, 1849
Series XVII: Rochester Daily Advertiser, Undated
Series XVIII: Sketches of Rochester, Undated
Series XIX: Legal Documents, 1832, 1840-1851, 1857
Series XX: Financial Documents, 1834-1859
Series XXI: Notes and Fragments, 1840-1859
Series XXII: Personal and Family Papers, 1832-1862
Series XXIII: Printed Material, 1830-1869
Series XXIV: Items Added in 2022, 1819-1880
Related Material at The New-York Historical Society
Manuscript Department; call phrase: BV O'Reilly. Correspondence, scrapbooks and bound volumes of assorted historical documents, memoranda and abstracts compiled by Henry O'Reilly; the material dates from 1784 to 1862. The bulk of the correspondence and scrapbooks span the 1840s, while the historical compilations cover the period 1784 through 1820. O'Reilly's scrapbooks address such topics as the development and building of the telegraph, railroad reform, inland navigation, American journalism, agriculture in New York State, and the Civil War. O'Reilly's Western Momentos documents the downfall of the Iroquois, Robert Morris' treaty with the Senecas, and pioneer settlements in New York State. Additional printed materials related to O'Reilly are held in the collections of the New-York Historical Society Library.
Agriculture -- New York (State).; American newspapers -- New York (State).; Canals -- New York (State); Postal service -- New York (State) -- Rochester.; Postmasters -- New York (State) -- Rochester.; Public schools -- New York (State) -- Rochester.; Railroads -- History; Steamboats -- New York (State); Telegraph -- United States.; Telegraph lines -- Design and construction; Williamsburg, Battle of, 1862; Erie Canal (N.Y.).; New York (State) -- History -- 1775-1865.; New York (State) -- History -- 1865-1950.; New York (State) -- Politics and government -- 19th century.; New York (State) -- Rochester -- Social life and customs.; New York (State) -- Rochester -- Politics and government.; Correspondence.; Financial records.; Legal records.; Notes (documents); Reports.; Pamphlets.; Circulars (fliers).; Clippings (information artifacts); Fliers (printed matter); Newspapers.; Proofs; Scrapbooks.; Albany Irish Repeal Association; Clinton League for Promoting the Completion of the Canal System; Demoine Navigation and Railroad Company; Irish and American Steamship Company; New-York Typographical Society; Rochester Athenaeum and Young Men's Association; Clinton, DeWitt, 1805-1833; Cornell, Ezra, 1807-1875; Delano, W. J.; Doane, Charles, active 1849; Ely, H. B.; O'Reilly, Henry Brooks
- Series I: General Correspondence, 1837-1873
  Scope and Contents note
  Series I contains correspondence relating to various business matters from 1837 through 1872.
  - Subseries I.A: Letters Received, 1837-1873
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
    - Letters Received: Unidentified (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Letters Received: A (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Letters Received: B (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Letters Received: C (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Letters Received: D (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Letters Received: E (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Letters Received: F (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Letters Received: G (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Letters Received: H (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Letters Received: K (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Letters Received: L (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Letters Received: M (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Letters Received: Mackenzie, Wm. L. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Letters Received: O (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Letters Received: P (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Letters Received: R (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Letters Received: S (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Letters Received: T (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Letters Received: V (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Letters Received: W (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Subseries I.B: Letters Sent, 1837-1858
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Letters Sent, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Letters Sent, 1837 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Letters Sent, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Letters Sent, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Letters Sent, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Letters Sent, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Letters Sent, 1846 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Letters Sent, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Letters Sent, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Letters Sent, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Letters Sent, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Letters Sent, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Subseries I.C: Letters Sent to The New-York Historical Society, 1858-1872
    - Letters Sent to The New-York Historical Society, 1858-1872 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Series II: Telegraph Enterprise, 1844-1861
  The bulk of the O'Reilly Papers falls within this series, the Telegraph Enterprise, which documents the establishment of the electric telegraph system in the United States. In addition to documenting the organization, construction, daily management and progress of various telegraph lines, this series contains material pertaining to the controversies, disputes and litigation in which O'Reilly became involved.
  - Subseries II.A: Correspondence, 1844-1860, Letters received arranged alphabetically by correspondent; letters sent arranged chronologically.
    - Letters Received: A (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Letters Received: Algeo, W.J. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Letters Received: Allen, W.S. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Letters Received: Alvord, J.N. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letters Received: Amsden, Ira R. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Letters Received: Arnold, Geo. B. (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Letters Received: Ashley, L. Seymour (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Letters Received: B-Be (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Letters Received: Bi-Bu (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Letters Received: Badollet, Howard (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Letters Received: Bain, Alexander (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Letters Received: Barbour and Porter (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Letters Received: Barbour, Lucian (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Letters Received: Barnes, E.F. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Letters Received: Barr, M.W. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Letters Received: Bateham, M.B. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Letters Received: Beale, G.W. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Letters Received: Beardslee, Geo. W. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Letters Received: Beaumont, R.J. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Letters Received: Beisel, F.V. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Letters Received: Bell, T.S. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Letters Received: Benedict and Boardman (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Letters Received: Benedict, G.W. (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Letters Received: Bickford, Jonathan (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Letters Received: Bigelow, John (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Letters Received: Bishop, Henry S. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Letters Received: Bourne, James T. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Letters Received: Bowly, J. Hollins (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Letters Received: Brady, Bart (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Letters Received: Briggs, W.G. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Letters Received: Bright, P.M. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Letters Received: Brooks, D. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Letters Received: Brooks, E. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Letters Received: Brooks, N.T. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Letters Received: Brown, F.A. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Letters Received: Brown, George T. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Letters Received: Brown, James C. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Letters Received: Buell, W.C. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Letters Received: Bumphrey, H. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Letters Received: Butler, C. Carroll (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Letters Received: Butts, Frances (?) (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Letters Received: C-Cl (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Letters Received: Co-Cu (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Letters Received: Callendar, William L. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Letters Received: Campbell, Jacob (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Letters Received: Cassell, J.J. (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Letters Received: Caswell, Homer (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Letters Received: Caton, J.D. (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Letters Received: Chadwick, Eli (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Letters Received: Chadwick, Rufus (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Letters Received: Channing, Wm. F. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Letters Received: Chase, Salmon P. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Letters Received: Chase, Seymour R. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Letters Received: Chester, E.W. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Letters Received: Child, Chas. W. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Letters Received: Clancy, Charles (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Letters Received: Clark, E.W. and Bros. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Letters Received: Coffin, Elijah (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Letters Received: Colburn, Fred M. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Letters Received: Collier, David L. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Letters Received: Compher, William (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Letters Received: Cook, F.C. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Letters Received: Corbiere, W.A. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Letters Received: Cornell, E. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Letters Received: Craig, D.H. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Letters Received: Crane, Benjamin P. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Letters Received: Creighton, E. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Letters Received: Creighton, James (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Letters Received: Cuming, T.B. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Letters Received: Curtis, D.S. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Letters Received: Curtis, D.S. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Letters Received: Cutler, James B. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Letters Received: D (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Letters Received: Daly, R.H. (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Letters Received: Darby, William (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Letters Received: Davis and Perkins (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Letters Received: Davis, G. (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Letters Received: Davis, J.C. (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Letters Received: Davis, William F. (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Letters Received: Dawson, George (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Letters Received: Day, H.H. (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Letters Received: Delano, W.J. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Letters Received: Delano, W.J. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Letters Received: Delano, W.J. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Letters Received: Delano, W.J. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Letters Received: Dickinson, D.S. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Letters Received: Doane, Charles (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Letters Received: Doane, Charles (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Letters Received: Doane, Charles (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Letters Received: Doolittle, H. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Letters Received: Doolittle, J.R. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Letters Received: Downing, Hugh (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Letters Received: Duncan, T.O. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Letters Received: E (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Letters Received: Earley, Wm. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Letters Received: Eddy, James (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Letters Received: Ellis, A.T. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Letters Received: Ellison, Wm. S. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Letters Received: Ellwanger, George (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Letters Received: Elwood, I.R. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Letters Received: Ely, B.F. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Letters Received: Ely, H.B. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Letters Received: Ely, H.B. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Letters Received: Ely, H.B. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Letters Received: F (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Letters Received: Farmer, M.G. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Letters Received: Field, J.M. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Letters Received: Fisk, John (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Letters Received: Fisk, John (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Letters Received: Fitch, W.O. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Letters Received: Forbes, G.V.H. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Letters Received: Forbes, Wm. H. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Letters Received: Francis, J.M. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Letters Received: Francis, J.M. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Letters Received: Francis, T. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Letters Received: G (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Letters Received: Gamble, Jno. M. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Letters Received: Gapaway, Kitty E.H. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Letters Received: Garlock, G.E. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Letters Received: Gavit, J.E. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Letters Received: Gholson, Davis and Miner (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Letters Received: Gholson, W.Y. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Letters Received: Gibbs, James S. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Letters Received: Gibbs, Montgomery (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Letters Received: Gilbert, Chas. J. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Letters Received: Gillet, J.T. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Letters Received: Gillet, R.H. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Letters Received: Gillet, R.H. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Letters Received: Gisborne, H.J. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Letters Received: Glass, J.P. (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Letters Received: Gray, J.A. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Letters Received: Green, Duff (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Letters Received: Greenhow, S.R. (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Letters Received: H (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Letters Received: Haight, D.C. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Letters Received: Haight, F.M. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Letters Received: Hall, Charles (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Letters Received: Hall, J.C. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Letters Received: Hanna, John H. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Letters Received: Hanna, Joshua (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Letters Received: Hanna, V.C. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Letters Received: Harlan, James (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Letters Received: Harris, W.A. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Letters Received: Haskins, R.W. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Letters Received: Hastings, W.F.B. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Letters Received: Hawkins, D.L. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Letters Received: Heath, J.K. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Letters Received: Hempstead, W. (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Letters Received: Henry, Joseph (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Letters Received: Hepburn, H.C. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Letters Received: Hepburn, H.C. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Letters Received: Hieskell, W.B. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Letters Received: Hill, C. (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Letters Received: Hine, C.C. (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Letters Received: Holloway, D.P. (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Letters Received: Holmes, C. (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Letters Received: Horner, John (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Letters Received: Hough, D.C. (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Letters Received: House, R.E. (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Letters Received: Howell, L. (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Letters Received: Hudson, C.H. (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Letters Received: Hughes, H.C. (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Letters Received: Hull, John E. (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Letters Received: Humphrey, C.M. (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Letters Received: Huntley, E.A. (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Letters Received: Ide, John S. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Letters Received: Ingle, John Jr. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Letters Received: Irwin, C.W. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Letters Received: J (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Letters Received: Jerome, L.W. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Letters Received: Jewell, Marshall (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Letters Received: Johnson, Chas. F. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Letters Received: Johnson, H.S. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Letters Received: Johnson, L.L. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Letters Received: Johnson, M.C. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Letters Received: Johnson, Moses (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Letters Received: Johnston, John A. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Letters Received: Jones, Albert E. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Letters Received: Jones, Alex (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Letters Received: Jones, George T. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Letters Received: Jones, Ira (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Letters Received: Jones, J.H. (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Letters Received: K (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Letters Received: Keating, E. (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Letters Received: Kendall, Amos (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Letters Received: Kidd, J.K. (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Letters Received: King, Fred (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Letters Received: King, Preston (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Letters Received: Kingsley, Edward (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Letters Received: L (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Letters Received: Lamb, David (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Letters Received: Lasscell, W.B. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Letters Received: Latapie, E. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Letters Received: Law, John (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Letters Received: Law, S.D. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Letters Received: Leadbeater, A. and E.H. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Letters Received: Lefferts, Marshall (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Letters Received: Lefferts, Marshall (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Letters Received: Lindsey, James M. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Letters Received: Livingston, J.B. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Letters Received: Livingston, Roggin and Co. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Letters Received: Lord, J.L. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Letters Received: Loughborough, J. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Letters Received: Lundy, G.L. (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Letters Received: Lyman, D.H. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Letters Received: Lyman, G. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Letters Received: Lyman, S. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Letters Received: Lynds, Elam (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Letters Received: M (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Letters Received: McGunnegle, George K. (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Letters Received: McKee, Wm. (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Letters Received: MacKenzie, George K. (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Letters Received: McRea, J.S. (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Letters Received: Mann, Alex (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Letters Received: Mann, D.C. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Letters Received: Mann, Donald (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Letters Received: Mann, Donald (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Letters Received: Marron, John (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Letters Received: Mather, J. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Letters Received: Mather, J. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Letters Received: Miller, C.T. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Letters Received: Mitchell, Wm. (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Letters Received: Moore, Joseph M. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Letters Received: Moorhead, J.K. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Letters Received: Morewood, Geo. B. (Box 11, Folder 12)